<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.4.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4002/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4002/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-06-27T16:28:59-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4002/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Koichi Nakayamada</title><entry><title type="html">DAHCI: Dino Run Blink</title><link href="http://localhost:4002/project/dino-run-blink/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="DAHCI: Dino Run Blink" /><published>2025-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2025-04-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4002/project/dino-run-blink</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4002/project/dino-run-blink/"><![CDATA[<p>This is the first project of DAHCI (De Anza Human-Computer Interaction), where we do projects about HCI involving EEG, BCI, ML, and more, which I’m in charge of as president.</p>

<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/aH-ho_wtZcI?si=CgdugHRHukbv3Wr6" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen=""></iframe>

<p>How this project works is pretty simple; it utilizes RMS (Root Mean Square) and threshold method to detect whether the user blinked or not in real-time, and if the blink is detected, the program virtually presses the space key to jump in Dino Run.</p>

<p>What I’ve learned, especially through threshold calibration for each test participant, was the EEG level differs significantly depending on people. The best threshold value could be 40 for some people and even 800 for some people. If we use it in real life, it’s better not to have calibration before starting to use it, so taking time with no blink to automatically adjust to the best threshold might be better. However, it’ll be more useful to use ML or the derivative method, so we don’t even need to use a threshold to detect.</p>

<p>You can check the source code from the GitHub link below<br />
https://github.com/deanzahci/dino-run-blink</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is the first project of DAHCI (De Anza Human-Computer Interaction), where we do projects about HCI involving EEG, BCI, ML, and more, which I’m in charge of as president.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4002/project/my-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Website" /><published>2025-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4002/project/my-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4002/project/my-website/"><![CDATA[<p>This website is designed to be <strong>as simple as possible</strong> while providing an effective platform to showcase my blogs, projects, and personal interests. It’s for anyone who wants to learn more about me and explore my work.</p>

<h1 id="goals">Goals</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Summarize my blogs and projects.</li>
  <li>Provide a clean, minimalist design.</li>
  <li>Help people who are curious about me easily understand my background and interests.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="technologies-used">Technologies Used</h1>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Jekyll</strong>: Static site generator.</li>
  <li><strong>HTML, CSS, JS</strong>: Frontend design and interactivity.</li>
  <li><strong>GitHub Pages</strong>: Deployment and hosting.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="features">Features</h1>

<ul>
  <li>A simple layout for <strong>blogs</strong> and <strong>projects</strong>.</li>
  <li>Personal information page for an easy introduction.</li>
  <li>Fully responsive and accessible design.</li>
</ul>

<p>Check out the source code on <a href="https://github.com/koichincom/my-website">GitHub</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This website is designed to be as simple as possible while providing an effective platform to showcase my blogs, projects, and personal interests. It’s for anyone who wants to learn more about me and explore my work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">About Me</title><link href="http://localhost:4002/project/about-me-profile/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="About Me" /><published>2024-12-15T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-12-15T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4002/project/about-me-profile</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4002/project/about-me-profile/"><![CDATA[<p>This is a personal project where I document my journey as a developer and share my thoughts about technology, design, and human-computer interaction.</p>

<h2 id="background">Background</h2>

<p>I’m passionate about creating meaningful experiences through technology. My interests span across web development, user interface design, and emerging technologies like brain-computer interfaces.</p>

<h2 id="skills--interests">Skills &amp; Interests</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Web Development</strong>: Creating clean, minimal websites with focus on user experience</li>
  <li><strong>UI/UX Design</strong>: Designing interfaces that are both beautiful and functional</li>
  <li><strong>Human-Computer Interaction</strong>: Exploring new ways humans can interact with computers</li>
  <li><strong>Research</strong>: Currently involved in DAHCI (De Anza Human-Computer Interaction) projects</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="goals">Goals</h2>

<p>My goal is to bridge the gap between technology and human needs, creating solutions that are not just functional but also delightful to use.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This is a personal project where I document my journey as a developer and share my thoughts about technology, design, and human-computer interaction.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Creative Coding Journey</title><link href="http://localhost:4002/project/creative-coding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Creative Coding Journey" /><published>2024-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-20T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4002/project/creative-coding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4002/project/creative-coding/"><![CDATA[<p>A collection of creative coding experiments and generative art projects that explore the intersection of mathematics, programming, and visual design.</p>

<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>

<p>This project showcases my exploration into creative programming, where code becomes a medium for artistic expression. Through various algorithms and mathematical concepts, I create visual compositions that are both aesthetically pleasing and technically interesting.</p>

<h2 id="key-concepts">Key Concepts</h2>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Generative Art</strong>: Using algorithms to create art that generates itself</li>
  <li><strong>Mathematical Beauty</strong>: Exploring patterns found in nature through code</li>
  <li><strong>Interactive Design</strong>: Creating responsive visual experiences</li>
  <li><strong>Processing &amp; p5.js</strong>: Utilizing creative coding frameworks</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="inspiration">Inspiration</h2>

<p>The beauty of creative coding lies in the unexpected. When mathematics meets creativity, the results can be surprisingly beautiful and often reveal patterns we never anticipated.</p>

<h2 id="future-directions">Future Directions</h2>

<p>I plan to explore more complex algorithms, integrate machine learning elements, and possibly venture into 3D generative art and interactive installations.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[A collection of creative coding experiments and generative art projects that explore the intersection of mathematics, programming, and visual design.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Lessons, 19 Years</title><link href="http://localhost:4002/blog/7-lessons-19-years/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Lessons, 19 Years" /><published>2024-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4002/blog/7-lessons-19-years</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4002/blog/7-lessons-19-years/"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li>You were born to be free. Take others’ advice with a grain of salt. Every action should ultimately connect to your happiness, and its process can bring pleasure to others.</li>
  <li>There is no inherent meaning in everyone’s life. Everything you care about can feel meaningless. So, it’s better to do what we find and define as meaningful. (≈ Active Nihilism)</li>
  <li>Don’t dwell on the past, nor cling to the future, but live in the moment. Reflecting on the past doesn’t shape our futures but wastes our time. (≈ mindfulness)</li>
  <li>Simplicity is everything. Once we grasp the intrinsic nature, the world is quite simple. (≈ minimalism)</li>
  <li>“Divide each difficulty into as many parts as is feasible and necessary to resolve it.” — René Descartes (≈ divide and conquer)</li>
  <li>We only need direction. We shouldn’t label ourselves.</li>
  <li>Avoid chasing perfection. Perfection leads only to wasted time. Make things work.</li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You were born to be free. Take others’ advice with a grain of salt. Every action should ultimately connect to your happiness, and its process can bring pleasure to others. There is no inherent meaning in everyone’s life. Everything you care about can feel meaningless. So, it’s better to do what we find and define as meaningful. (≈ Active Nihilism) Don’t dwell on the past, nor cling to the future, but live in the moment. Reflecting on the past doesn’t shape our futures but wastes our time. (≈ mindfulness) Simplicity is everything. Once we grasp the intrinsic nature, the world is quite simple. (≈ minimalism) “Divide each difficulty into as many parts as is feasible and necessary to resolve it.” — René Descartes (≈ divide and conquer) We only need direction. We shouldn’t label ourselves. Avoid chasing perfection. Perfection leads only to wasted time. Make things work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Crossroads of Phone Addiction</title><link href="http://localhost:4002/blog/phone-addiction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Crossroads of Phone Addiction" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4002/blog/phone-addiction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4002/blog/phone-addiction/"><![CDATA[<p>It should be because of your phone if you feel you aren’t doing well. It consumes your time and is known as life. But you’ve already known this and don’t need to understand why you should do that anymore. I’ve recognized it for a long time, too. I deleted all social media apps on my phone, turned the gray color filter on, left only four apps on my home screen, and so on. But my screen time is still around 6 hours a day, and it gets 10 hours or more on a terrible day. It’s ridiculous that I spend a quarter of my life on my phone, but how does it happen? For me, it was because of YouTube addiction. It was my bestie and, simultaneously, my Arch-enemy.</p>

<p>I made three rules, but they’re pretty simple. They should only watch YouTube videos if they are for learning, search videos only from the search box, not from the recommendations, and meditate for 10 seconds when I’m dying to watch YouTube. I installed ScreenZen on my iPhone to forbid watching YouTube on my smartphone. Additionally, I installed an extension called Unhook on my Mac browser to restrict the YouTube feature to only searching videos. I made this decision the day before last night and did pretty well yesterday. I did pretty simple things, but I started taking specific actions.</p>

<p>By this process, I specified the main problem, set a clear-cut rule, and created an environment that forced me to follow it. You can make your own rules following these steps. Then, we should admit that we’re addicted to our phones to escape from tasks that we don’t want to think about. I’m on my way to overcoming addiction, and I’ve tried it many times, but I can do that now. This is a question of our honors and determinations. If we can say goodbye to our phones and their addictions, we’ll get everything: a lot of time, concentration, life satisfaction, and so on. This is a fork in the road.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It should be because of your phone if you feel you aren’t doing well. It consumes your time and is known as life. But you’ve already known this and don’t need to understand why you should do that anymore. I’ve recognized it for a long time, too. I deleted all social media apps on my phone, turned the gray color filter on, left only four apps on my home screen, and so on. But my screen time is still around 6 hours a day, and it gets 10 hours or more on a terrible day. It’s ridiculous that I spend a quarter of my life on my phone, but how does it happen? For me, it was because of YouTube addiction. It was my bestie and, simultaneously, my Arch-enemy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running Away from Pain</title><link href="http://localhost:4002/blog/running-away-from-pain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running Away from Pain" /><published>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4002/blog/running-away-from-pain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4002/blog/running-away-from-pain/"><![CDATA[<p>I became a proactive truant and got depressed in my first year of high school because of the intimidating and closed environment and teachers. While at home, I was thinking about my purpose of attending school, studying, and living all the time. Eventually, I got a straightforward and obvious but essential purpose for living.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The reason why I am living is just to be happy. And if something bothers me, I can and should run away from it to be satisfied.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After I got this value, my depression almost recovered, and I felt free. I transferred to a famous online high school in Japan in my second year. It was a great decision. I could make great friends and meet great teachers. More than anything else, because I had more free time, I was inspired by a classmate to participate in extracurricular activities such as organizing events and joining presentation competitions, which allowed me to learn about a new world that I had never known before. Also, it is a high school known as an advanced education system; there was an academic path support division of universities overseas, which kind of opportunity is rare in Japan. Because there was such support, I could join the online Oxford summer program and learn about the system of foreign universities to grasp and think about them deeply and rethink my life goals. As a result, I am now in a U.S. community college and aiming to transfer to a four-year university. I wish I had recognized myself sooner and escaped sooner before I became depressed.</p>

<p>So far, it’s been my story; I want to write what I can say from now on. We have to endure, but we also have to escape. Without context and background, we can’t decide which option to take. We need to consider whether there are enthusiastic dreams beyond the pain. We need to think critically and ask ourselves if we think so. Unsurprisingly, our lifetime is finite, and everyone will die. So, when we think about how to make the most of our limited time and be happy, it is highly contradictory and self-destructive to put up with painful situations that do not align with our dreams and goals. However, quitting what you have kept doing is risky, and you might need to find out whether the pain leads you to your enthusiastic dream. In that case, it will be very effective to take your time for holidays or vacations and do journaling or stuff like that to rest your mind. By taking distance from the pain temporarily, you observe your situation objectively. Running away from the pain is the opposite of running away from life. It entails happiness, dreams, and real life. The mindset we need to have is not a binary choice of whether to run away. It’s moving forward toward your objects to be happy. Regardless of what others say, your life is yours, and my life is mine.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I became a proactive truant and got depressed in my first year of high school because of the intimidating and closed environment and teachers. While at home, I was thinking about my purpose of attending school, studying, and living all the time. Eventually, I got a straightforward and obvious but essential purpose for living.]]></summary></entry></feed>