<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-29T16:41:22-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Koichi Nakayamada</title><subtitle>Personal Blog and Projects</subtitle><entry><title type="html">De Anza Neurotech Club</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/dant/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="De Anza Neurotech Club" /><published>2024-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-17T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/dant</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/dant/"><![CDATA[<p>The De Anza Neurotechnology Club (DANT) is a passionate community dedicated to exploring the exciting field of 
neurotechnology. Situated in Silicon Valley, our club provides opportunities for enthusiasts to learn from scratch, 
collaborate on innovative projects, and turn dreams into reality.</p>

<p><a href="https://linktr.ee/deanzaneurotech">Visit our resources and get involved here.</a></p>

<hr />

<h2 id="vision">Vision</h2>

<p>At DANT, we envision a <strong>neurotechnology enthusiast community</strong> where everyone, regardless of their background, can:</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Learn neurotechnology from scratch.</strong></li>
  <li>Collaborate on impactful projects.</li>
  <li>Pursue their dreams with real-world results and opportunities, utilizing the resources Silicon Valley offers.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h2 id="missions">Missions</h2>

<p>Our missions embody the spirit of exploration, learning, and achievement:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Achieve Results:</strong> Work on both internal and external neurotechnology projects that push boundaries.</li>
  <li><strong>Join Competitions:</strong> Compete in hackathons and competitions to win recognition and prizes.</li>
  <li><strong>Build Community:</strong> Create a serious yet fun learning environment where everyone can grow together, regardless of</li>
  <li>their prior experience.</li>
</ol>

<hr />

<h2 id="key-initiatives">Key Initiatives</h2>

<h3 id="1-internal-and-external-projects">1. <strong>Internal and External Projects</strong></h3>
<p>We focus on research and projects, including:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Brain-Computer Interfaces (BCI):</strong> Designing tools that bridge technology and the human mind.</li>
  <li><strong>Cognitive Enhancement:</strong> Exploring technologies that improve learning and memory.</li>
  <li><strong>Collaborative Partnerships:</strong> Working with companies, startups, and professionals to bring ideas to life.</li>
</ul>

<h3 id="2-competitions-and-hackathons">2. <strong>Competitions and Hackathons</strong></h3>
<p>We actively participate in hackathons and global neurotechnology challenges. Our members have the opportunity to showcase 
their skills, network with professionals, and earn recognition for their work.</p>

<h3 id="3-learning-from-scratch">3. <strong>Learning from Scratch</strong></h3>
<p>DANT is open to all—whether you’re a seasoned coder or a curious beginner. Our workshops, tutorials, and peer-to-peer 
support ensure everyone can grow their knowledge and skills.</p>

<hr />

<h2 id="why-join-dant">Why Join DANT?</h2>

<p>By joining DANT, you’ll:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Learn New Skills:</strong> Dive deep into neurotechnology, coding, and research methodologies.</li>
  <li><strong>Collaborate:</strong> Work with like-minded peers on real-world challenges.</li>
  <li><strong>Network:</strong> Connect with industry professionals and explore career opportunities.</li>
  <li><strong>Achieve Results:</strong> Translate your efforts into tangible outcomes, from awards to products.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I'm trying to start a Neurotechology enthusiast club at De Anza College.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">My Personal Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/my-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Personal Website" /><published>2024-11-16T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2024-11-16T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/my-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/my-website/"><![CDATA[<h2 id="overview">Overview</h2>
<p>This website serves as my personal portfolio and blog, built with a focus on simplicity and functionality. Using Jekyll, 
I streamlined content management by converting Markdown files into HTML and leveraged features like front matter to integrate 
JavaScript for dynamic elements such as date calculations. The project helped me deepen my understanding of web development 
fundamentals, including structuring and styling a website effectively.</p>

<h2 id="website-structure">Website Structure</h2>
<p>The site is designed with a clean navigation bar at the top, providing easy access to the following sections:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Homepage</strong>: A brief introduction to who I am and what I do.</li>
  <li><strong>Projects</strong>: Highlights of my work, with start and end dates calculated dynamically using JavaScript.</li>
  <li><strong>Blog</strong>: A collection of my thoughts and experiences, presented with clear formatting for readability.</li>
  <li><strong>About</strong>: A short biography with links to my social profiles for networking.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="design-philosophy">Design Philosophy</h2>
<p>I prioritized a simple and intuitive design to enhance user experience. The navigation bar and layout are clean and 
minimalistic, allowing users to focus on the content. Responsive design ensures the site is accessible across all devices.</p>

<h2 id="technical-highlights">Technical Highlights</h2>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Jekyll Integration</strong>: Simplified content management with Markdown and front matter.</li>
  <li><strong>Dynamic Elements</strong>: Used JavaScript to calculate project durations and display them dynamically.</li>
  <li><strong>GitHub Pages Deployment</strong>: The website is deployed using GitHub Pages, making it easy to host and maintain.</li>
  <li>The source code is available in the <a href="https://github.com/koichincom/my-website">GitHub Repository</a></li>
  <li><strong>Learning Outcomes</strong>: Through this project, I improved my understanding of website structure, responsive design, and</li>
  <li>efficient content management systems.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="future-improvements">Future Improvements</h2>
<p>I plan to expand the functionality by adding:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Interactive elements such as recommended posts or animations.</li>
  <li>Advanced tracking features for project milestones.</li>
  <li>Enhanced accessibility to ensure inclusivity for all users.</li>
</ul>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[My personal website for my portfolio and blogs.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Seven Lessons, 19 Years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/7-lessons-19-years/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Seven Lessons, 19 Years" /><published>2024-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/7-lessons-19-years</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/7-lessons-19-years/"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li>
    <p>You were born to be free. Take others’ advice with a pinch of salt. Every action should eventually connected to your 
happiness, and its process can pleasure others.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>There’s no meaning in everyone’s life. Everything you care about is meaningless. So, do what you feel is meaningful 
and enthusiastic, and do it with great people. (≈ positive nihilism)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Never mind the past, never stick to the future, but live at the moment. Thinking about the past never creates your 
future. Don’t waste your time. (≈ mindfulness)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Own only what you need, and love what you have. It’s the same thing in thinking. Get focused on what you need, and be 
enthusiastic about what you do. (≈ minimalism)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Separate your problem. Each task must be accessible. “Divide each difficulty into as many parts as is feasible and 
necessary to resolve it.” — René Descartes (≈ divide and conquer)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Don’t make your current status your identity. Time is constantly moving, and your effort should change your status. 
If you stick to your status, you’ll never progress, and you’ll regret it. You only need direction, not satisfaction 
with where you’re now. (≈ growth mindset)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Never pursue perfection. Perfection brings nothing but wasted time. Make things work. Get things done.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[7 lessons I've learned with exclusiating painin 19 years of my life]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Crossroads of Phone Addiction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/the-crossroads-of-phone-addiction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Crossroads of Phone Addiction" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/the-crossroads-of-phone-addiction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/the-crossroads-of-phone-addiction/"><![CDATA[<p>It should be because of your phone if you feel you aren’t doing well. It consumes your time and is known as life. But 
you’ve already known this and don’t need to understand why you should do that anymore. I’ve recognized it for a long time, 
too. I deleted all social media apps on my phone, turned the gray color filter on, left only four apps on my home screen, 
and so on. But my screen time is still around 6 hours a day, and it gets 10 hours or more on a terrible day. It’s ridiculous 
that I spend a quarter of my life on my phone, but how does it happen? For me, it was because of YouTube addiction. 
It was my bestie and, simultaneously, my Arch-enemy.</p>

<p>I made three rules, but they’re pretty simple. They should only watch YouTube videos if they are for learning, search 
videos only from the search box, not from the recommendations, and meditate for 10 seconds when I’m dying to watch YouTube. 
I installed ScreenZen on my iPhone to forbid watching YouTube on my smartphone. Additionally, I installed an extension called 
Unhook on my Mac browser to restrict the YouTube feature to only searching videos. I made this decision the day before 
last night and did pretty well yesterday. I did pretty simple things, but I started taking specific actions.</p>

<p>By this process, I specified the main problem, set a clear-cut rule, and created an environment that forced me to follow it. 
You can make your own rules following these steps. Then, we should admit that we’re addicted to our phones to escape from 
tasks that we don’t want to think about. I’m on my way to overcoming addiction, and I’ve tried it many times, but I can do 
that now. This is a question of our honors and determinations. If we can say goodbye to our phones and their addictions, 
we’ll get everything: a lot of time, concentration, life satisfaction, and so on. This is a fork in the road.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Phone addiction is a serious problem.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running Away from Pain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running Away from Pain" /><published>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain/"><![CDATA[<p>I became a proactive truant and got depressed in my first year of high school because of the intimidating and closed 
environment and teachers. While at home, I was thinking about my purpose of attending school, studying, 
and living all the time. Eventually, I got a straightforward and obvious but essential purpose for living.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The reason why I am living is just to be happy. And if something bothers me to be happy, I can and should run away from it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>We need to consider it well when we make big decisions. However, this simple policy does work. After I got this value, 
my depression almost recovered, and I felt free. I transferred to a famous online high school in Japan in my second year. 
It was a great decision. I could make great friends and meet great teachers. More than anything else, because I had more 
free time, I was inspired by a classmate to participate in extracurricular activities such as organizing events and joining 
presentation competitions, which allowed me to learn about a new world that I had never known before. Also, its high school 
is known as an advanced education system; there was an academic path support division of universities overseas, which kind 
of opportunity is rare in Japan. Because there was such support, I could join the online Oxford summer program and learn 
about the system of foreign universities to grasp and think about them deeply and rethink my life goals. As a result, I 
am in a U.S. community college and aiming to transfer to 4 years university. I wish I had recognized myself sooner and 
escaped sooner before I became depressed.</p>

<p>So far, it’s been my story; I want to write what I can say from it from now on. We have a time we have to endure, but we 
also have a time we need to escape. Without context and background, we cannot decide which option to take. We need to 
consider whether there are enthusiastic dreams beyond the pain. We need to think critically and ask ourselves if we think so. 
Unsurprisingly, our lifetime is finite, and everyone will die. So, when we think about how to make the most of our limited 
time and be happy, it is highly contradictory and self-destructive to put up with painful situations that do not align with 
our dreams and goals. However, quitting what you have kept doing is risky, and you might need to find out whether the pain 
leads you to your enthusiastic dream. In that case, it will be very effective to take your time for holidays or vacations 
and do journaling or stuff like that to rest your mind. By taking distance from the pain temporarily, you observe your 
situation objectively. Running away from the pain is the opposite of running away from life. It entails happiness, dreams, 
and real life. The mindset we need to have is not a binary choice of whether to run away. It’s moving forward toward your 
objects to be happy. Regardless of what others say, your life is yours, and my life is mine.</p>

<p>I rewrote this post to learn more about how I wrote it and its English expressions. While doing it, I felt nostalgic, 
and my mindset improved. Even if you or I feel overwhelmed and disappointed by ourselves, we can feel our progress and 
improvements in the future. The past isn’t back, but we are living in the now, and we can shape our future.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The story I became a proactive truant and now I'm in the US to study Computer Science.]]></summary></entry></feed>