<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-17T06:09:14-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Koichi Nakayamada</title><subtitle>Personal Blog and Projects</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Cross Roads of Phone Addiction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/a-cross-roads-of-phone-addiction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Cross Roads of Phone Addiction" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/a-cross-roads-of-phone-addiction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/a-cross-roads-of-phone-addiction/"><![CDATA[<p>It should be because of your phone if you feel you aren’t doing well. It consumes your time and is known as life. But you’ve already known this and don’t need to understand why you should do that anymore. I’ve recognized it for a long time, too. I deleted all social media apps on my phone, turned the gray color filter on, left only four apps on my home screen, and so on. But my screen time is still around 6 hours a day, and it gets 10 hours or more on a terrible day. It’s ridiculous that I spend a quarter of my life on my phone, but how does it happen? For me, it was because of YouTube addiction. It was my bestie and, simultaneously, my Arch-enemy.</p>

<p>I made three rules, but they’re pretty simple. They should only watch YouTube videos if they are for learning, search videos only from the search box, not from the recommendations, and meditate for 10 seconds when I’m dying to watch YouTube. I installed ScreenZen on my iPhone to forbid watching YouTube on my smartphone. Additionally, I installed an extension called Unhook on my Mac browser to restrict the YouTube feature to only searching videos. I made this decision the day before last night and did pretty well yesterday. I did pretty simple things, but I started taking specific actions.</p>

<p>By this process, I specified the main problem, set a clear-cut rule, and created an environment that forced me to follow it. You can make your own rules following these steps. Then, we should admit that we’re addicted to our phones to escape from tasks that we don’t want to think about. I’m on my way to overcoming addiction, and I’ve tried it many times, but I can do that now. This is a question of our honors and determinations. If we can say goodbye to our phones and their addictions, we’ll get everything: a lot of time, concentration, life satisfaction, and so on. This is a fork in the road.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the journey of overcoming phone addiction by setting rules and creating a conducive environment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Things I Learned in 19 Years of my Life</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/seven-things-i-learned-in-19-years-of-my-life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Things I Learned in 19 Years of my Life" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/seven-things-i-learned-in-19-years-of-my-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/seven-things-i-learned-in-19-years-of-my-life/"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li>
    <p>You were born to be free. Take others’ advice with a pinch of salt. Every action should eventually connected to your happiness, and its process can pleasure others.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>There’s no meaning in everyone’s life. Everything you care about is meaningless. So, do what you feel is meaningful and enthusiastic, and do it with great people. (≈ positive nihilism)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Never mind the past, never stick to the future, but live in the moment. Thinking about the past never creates your future. Don’t waste your time. (≈ mindfulness)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Own only what you need, and love what you have. It’s the same thing in thinking. Get focused on what you need, and be enthusiastic about what you do. (≈ minimalism)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Separate your problem. Each task must be accessible. “Divide each difficulty into as many parts as is feasible and necessary to resolve it.” — René Descartes (≈ divide and conquer)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Don’t make your current status your identity. Time is constantly moving, and your effort should change your status. If you stick to your status, you’ll never progress, and you’ll regret it. You only need direction, not satisfaction with where you’re now.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Never pursue perfection. Perfection brings nothing but wasted time. Make things work. Get things done.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the journey of overcoming phone addiction by setting rules and creating a conducive environment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">koichin.com</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/koichin.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="koichin.com" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/koichin.com</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/koichin.com/"><![CDATA[<h1 id="overview">Overview</h1>
<p>This website is a personal portfolio and blog that showcases my journey as a student majoring in Computer Science. It also provides a platform to share projects, ideas, and experiences that reflect my growth and aspirations in Silicon Valley. The website’s primary aim is to present information in a clean, structured, and professional manner while maintaining simplicity and functionality.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="website-structure">Website Structure</h1>

<h2 id="1-homepage">1. <strong>Homepage</strong></h2>
<p>The homepage serves as an introduction to who I am. It briefly highlights my key interests, achievements, and current activities. It also includes links to the primary sections of the website:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Blog</li>
  <li>Projects</li>
  <li>About Me</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="2-blog">2. <strong>Blog</strong></h2>
<p>The blog is a collection of posts where I share insights, personal experiences, and thoughts on various topics. These posts are structured with:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Date of publication</strong>: Displayed prominently to indicate when the content was written.</li>
  <li><strong>Title</strong>: A descriptive and concise heading for each post.</li>
  <li><strong>Description</strong>: A short summary of the post.</li>
  <li><strong>Content</strong>: Detailed discussions or narratives, formatted for readability.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="3-projects">3. <strong>Projects</strong></h2>
<p>The projects section highlights my work and contributions. It is designed to track the lifecycle of each project with:</p>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Start and End Dates</strong>: Used to calculate the duration of each project.</li>
  <li><strong>Status</strong>: Indicates whether the project is ongoing or completed.</li>
  <li><strong>Description</strong>: Provides context and details about the project.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="4-about">4. <strong>About</strong></h2>
<p>This page introduces me in greater detail, featuring:</p>
<ul>
  <li>A profile picture styled with CSS to be visually appealing.</li>
  <li>A short biography summarizing my academic background, interests, and goals.</li>
  <li>Contact information with a <strong>mailto</strong> link for easy communication.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="5-responsive-design">5. <strong>Responsive Design</strong></h2>
<p>The entire website is responsive, ensuring optimal user experience across various devices. The layout adjusts seamlessly to different screen sizes without compromising on readability or functionality.</p>

<hr />

<h1 id="key-features-and-goals">Key Features and Goals</h1>

<h2 id="1-minimalist-design">1. <strong>Minimalist Design</strong></h2>
<p>The design emphasizes simplicity, using clean layouts, neutral colors, and sufficient spacing for a professional appearance. This approach enhances user focus on the content.</p>

<h2 id="2-dynamic-functionality">2. <strong>Dynamic Functionality</strong></h2>
<p>Features like:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Status and duration tracking for projects.</li>
  <li>JSON-LD structured data for search engine optimization (SEO).</li>
  <li>JavaScript to dynamically display recommended posts or additional interactive elements.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="3-seo-optimization">3. <strong>SEO Optimization</strong></h2>
<p>Meta descriptions, keywords, and structured data are implemented across pages to ensure the website ranks effectively on search engines. This includes:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Personalized metadata for each blog post and project.</li>
  <li>Structured data using JSON-LD to define my professional profile and content.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="4-scalability">4. <strong>Scalability</strong></h2>
<p>The website is built to accommodate future enhancements, such as:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Adding new sections or features without disrupting the existing structure.</li>
  <li>Differentiating the Blog and Projects sections while maintaining shared components for efficiency.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h1 id="future-plans">Future Plans</h1>
<ul>
  <li><strong>Expand the Projects Section</strong>: Incorporate more detailed tracking and visualization for project progress, including timelines and milestones.</li>
  <li><strong>Enhance User Engagement</strong>: Add features like recommended posts, interactive elements, or animations.</li>
  <li><strong>Improve Accessibility</strong>: Ensure the website adheres to accessibility standards for all users.</li>
  <li><strong>Continuous Learning</strong>: Use this website as a platform to experiment with new technologies and improve my skills in web development.</li>
</ul>

<hr />

<h1 id="summary">Summary</h1>
<p>This website is more than just a portfolio—it’s a reflection of my journey, interests, and aspirations. It blends simplicity with functionality, aiming to create a platform that is both personal and professional. As I continue to grow, so will this website, serving as a dynamic record of my learning and achievements.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This website, koichin.com, is a simple personal project that shows my projects, blog posts, and basic info. I used technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Ruby, YAML, and Jekyll.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running Away from Pain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running Away from Pain" /><published>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain/"><![CDATA[<p>I became a proactive truant and got depressed in my first year of high school because of the intimidating and closed environment and teachers. While at home, I was thinking about my purpose of attending school, studying, and living all the time. Eventually, I got a straightforward and obvious but essential purpose for living.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The reason why I am living is just to be happy. And if something bothers me to be happy, I can and should run away from it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>We need to consider it well when we make big decisions. However, this simple policy does work. After I got this value, my depression almost recovered, and I felt free. I transferred to a famous online high school in Japan in my second year. It was a great decision. I could make great friends and meet great teachers. More than anything else, because I had more free time, I was inspired by a classmate to participate in extracurricular activities such as organizing events and joining presentation competitions, which allowed me to learn about a new world that I had never known before. Also, its high school is known as an advanced education system; there was an academic path support division of universities overseas, which kind of opportunity is rare in Japan. Because there was such support, I could join the online Oxford summer program and learn about the system of foreign universities to grasp and think about them deeply and rethink my life goals. As a result, I am in a U.S. community college and aiming to transfer to 4 years university. I wish I had recognized myself sooner and escaped sooner before I became depressed.</p>

<p>So far, it’s been my story; I want to write what I can say from it from now on. We have a time we have to endure, but we also have a time we need to escape. Without context and background, we cannot decide which option to take. We need to consider whether there are enthusiastic dreams beyond the pain. We need to think critically and ask ourselves if we think so. Unsurprisingly, our lifetime is finite, and everyone will die. So, when we think about how to make the most of our limited time and be happy, it is highly contradictory and self-destructive to put up with painful situations that do not align with our dreams and goals. However, quitting what you have kept doing is risky, and you might need to find out whether the pain leads you to your enthusiastic dream. In that case, it will be very effective to take your time for holidays or vacations and do journaling or stuff like that to rest your mind. By taking distance from the pain temporarily, you observe your situation objectively. Running away from the pain is the opposite of running away from life. It entails happiness, dreams, and real life. The mindset we need to have is not a binary choice of whether to run away. It’s moving forward toward your objects to be happy. Regardless of what others say, your life is yours, and my life is mine.</p>

<p>I rewrote this post to learn more about how I wrote it and its English expressions. While doing it, I felt nostalgic, and my mindset improved. Even if you or I feel overwhelmed and disappointed by ourselves, we can feel our progress and improvements in the future. The past isn’t back, but we are living in the now, and we can shape our future.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The story I became a proactive truant and now I'm in the US to study Computer Science.]]></summary></entry></feed>