<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-11-17T05:17:54-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Koichi Nakayamada</title><subtitle>Personal Blog and Projects</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A Cross Roads of Phone Addiction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/a-cross-roads-of-phone-addiction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Cross Roads of Phone Addiction" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/a-cross-roads-of-phone-addiction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/a-cross-roads-of-phone-addiction/"><![CDATA[<p>It should be because of your phone if you feel you aren’t doing well. It consumes your time and is known as life. But you’ve already known this and don’t need to understand why you should do that anymore. I’ve recognized it for a long time, too. I deleted all social media apps on my phone, turned the gray color filter on, left only four apps on my home screen, and so on. But my screen time is still around 6 hours a day, and it gets 10 hours or more on a terrible day. It’s ridiculous that I spend a quarter of my life on my phone, but how does it happen? For me, it was because of YouTube addiction. It was my bestie and, simultaneously, my Arch-enemy.</p>

<p>I made three rules, but they’re pretty simple. They should only watch YouTube videos if they are for learning, search videos only from the search box, not from the recommendations, and meditate for 10 seconds when I’m dying to watch YouTube. I installed ScreenZen on my iPhone to forbid watching YouTube on my smartphone. Additionally, I installed an extension called Unhook on my Mac browser to restrict the YouTube feature to only searching videos. I made this decision the day before last night and did pretty well yesterday. I did pretty simple things, but I started taking specific actions.</p>

<p>By this process, I specified the main problem, set a clear-cut rule, and created an environment that forced me to follow it. You can make your own rules following these steps. Then, we should admit that we’re addicted to our phones to escape from tasks that we don’t want to think about. I’m on my way to overcoming addiction, and I’ve tried it many times, but I can do that now. This is a question of our honors and determinations. If we can say goodbye to our phones and their addictions, we’ll get everything: a lot of time, concentration, life satisfaction, and so on. This is a fork in the road.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Exploring the journey of overcoming phone addiction by setting rules and creating a conducive environment.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/my-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Website" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/my-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/my-website/"><![CDATA[<p>I’m still working on this website. Yeah, it’s so hard.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[test]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running Away from Pain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running Away from Pain" /><published>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/running-away-from-pain/"><![CDATA[<p>I became a proactive truant and got depressed in my first year of high school because of the intimidating and closed environment and teachers. While at home, I was thinking about my purpose of attending school, studying, and living all the time. Eventually, I got a straightforward and obvious but essential purpose for living.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The reason why I am living is just to be happy. And if something bothers me to be happy, I can and should run away from it.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>We need to consider it well when we make big decisions. However, this simple policy does work. After I got this value, my depression almost recovered, and I felt free. I transferred to a famous online high school in Japan in my second year. It was a great decision. I could make great friends and meet great teachers. More than anything else, because I had more free time, I was inspired by a classmate to participate in extracurricular activities such as organizing events and joining presentation competitions, which allowed me to learn about a new world that I had never known before. Also, its high school is known as an advanced education system; there was an academic path support division of universities overseas, which kind of opportunity is rare in Japan. Because there was such support, I could join the online Oxford summer program and learn about the system of foreign universities to grasp and think about them deeply and rethink my life goals. As a result, I am in a U.S. community college and aiming to transfer to 4 years university. I wish I had recognized myself sooner and escaped sooner before I became depressed.</p>

<p>So far, it’s been my story; I want to write what I can say from it from now on. We have a time we have to endure, but we also have a time we need to escape. Without context and background, we cannot decide which option to take. We need to consider whether there are enthusiastic dreams beyond the pain. We need to think critically and ask ourselves if we think so. Unsurprisingly, our lifetime is finite, and everyone will die. So, when we think about how to make the most of our limited time and be happy, it is highly contradictory and self-destructive to put up with painful situations that do not align with our dreams and goals. However, quitting what you have kept doing is risky, and you might need to find out whether the pain leads you to your enthusiastic dream. In that case, it will be very effective to take your time for holidays or vacations and do journaling or stuff like that to rest your mind. By taking distance from the pain temporarily, you observe your situation objectively. Running away from the pain is the opposite of running away from life. It entails happiness, dreams, and real life. The mindset we need to have is not a binary choice of whether to run away. It’s moving forward toward your objects to be happy. Regardless of what others say, your life is yours, and my life is mine.</p>

<p>I rewrote this post to learn more about how I wrote it and its English expressions. While doing it, I felt nostalgic, and my mindset improved. Even if you or I feel overwhelmed and disappointed by ourselves, we can feel our progress and improvements in the future. The past isn’t back, but we are living in the now, and we can shape our future.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The story I became a proactive truant and now I'm in the US to study Computer Science.]]></summary></entry></feed>