<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-01-29T18:10:19-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Koichi Nakayamada</title><entry><title type="html">My Website</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/project/my-website/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="My Website" /><published>2025-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-25T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/project/my-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/project/my-website/"><![CDATA[<p>This website is designed to be <strong>as simple as possible</strong> while providing an effective platform to showcase my blogs, projects, and personal interests. It’s for anyone who wants to learn more about me and explore my work.</p>

<h1 id="goals">Goals</h1>
<ul>
  <li>Summarize my blogs and projects.</li>
  <li>Provide a clean, minimalist design.</li>
  <li>Help people who are curious about me easily understand my background and interests.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="technologies-used">Technologies Used</h1>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Jekyll</strong>: Static site generator.</li>
  <li><strong>HTML, CSS, JS</strong>: Frontend design and interactivity.</li>
  <li><strong>GitHub Pages</strong>: Deployment and hosting.</li>
</ul>

<h1 id="features">Features</h1>

<ul>
  <li>A simple layout for <strong>blogs</strong> and <strong>projects</strong>.</li>
  <li>Personal information page for an easy introduction.</li>
  <li>Fully responsive and accessible design.</li>
</ul>

<p>Check out the source code on <a href="https://github.com/koichincom/my-website">GitHub</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="project" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[This website is designed to be as simple as possible while providing an effective platform to showcase my blogs, projects, and personal interests. It’s for anyone who wants to learn more about me and explore my work.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2025</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2025" /><published>2025-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2025-01-01T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/2025</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/2025/"><![CDATA[<p>I will write a short blog for the new year to clarify my head. 2025 is a year of victory or defeat. The main topic is the transfer application. I will apply to UC Berkeley and UC San Diego and want good news from both. To achieve it, I need to maintain my GPA, run two clubs I’ll be in charge of the president, do some tutoring at school, and get explicit results from ML and Neurotech projects. In addition, it’s super important to eat, sleep, and exercise well to maintain my body. I will sense nostalgia for this year and the future, as they will be the folk on the road. I’ll think about priorities and do things with a do-or-die attitude.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I will write a short blog for the new year to clarify my head. 2025 is a year of victory or defeat. The main topic is the transfer application. I will apply to UC Berkeley and UC San Diego and want good news from both. To achieve it, I need to maintain my GPA, run two clubs I’ll be in charge of the president, do some tutoring at school, and get explicit results from ML and Neurotech projects. In addition, it’s super important to eat, sleep, and exercise well to maintain my body. I will sense nostalgia for this year and the future, as they will be the folk on the road. I’ll think about priorities and do things with a do-or-die attitude.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">7 Lessons, 19 Years</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/7-lessons/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="7 Lessons, 19 Years" /><published>2024-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-09-08T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/7-lessons</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/7-lessons/"><![CDATA[<ol>
  <li>
    <p>You were born to be free. Take others’ advice with a pinch of salt. Every action should eventually connected to your 
happiness, and its process can pleasure others.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>There’s no meaning in everyone’s life. Everything you care about is meaningless. So, please do what you feel is meaningful 
and enthusiastic, and do it with great people. (≈ positive nihilism)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Never mind the past, never stick to the future, but live in the moment. Thinking about the past never creates your 
future. Don’t waste your time. (≈ mindfulness)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Own only what you need, and love what you have. It’s the same thing in thinking. Get focused on what you need, and be 
enthusiastic about what you do. (≈ minimalism)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Separate your problem. Each task must be accessible. “Divide each difficulty into as many parts as is feasible and 
necessary to resolve it.” — René Descartes (≈ divide and conquer)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Don’t make your current status your identity. Time is constantly moving, and your effort should change your status. 
If you stick to your status, you’ll never progress and regret it. You only need direction, not satisfaction 
with where you’re now. (≈ growth mindset)</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>Never pursue perfection. Perfection brings nothing but wasted time. Make things work. Get things done.</p>
  </li>
</ol>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[You were born to be free. Take others’ advice with a pinch of salt. Every action should eventually connected to your happiness, and its process can pleasure others.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Crossroads of Phone Addiction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/phone-addiction/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Crossroads of Phone Addiction" /><published>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/phone-addiction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/phone-addiction/"><![CDATA[<p>It should be because of your phone if you feel you aren’t doing well. It consumes your time and is known as life. But you’ve already known this and don’t need to understand why you should do that anymore. I’ve recognized it for a long time, too. I deleted all social media apps on my phone, turned the gray color filter on, left only four apps on my home screen, and so on. But my screen time is still around 6 hours a day, and it gets 10 hours or more on a terrible day. It’s ridiculous that I spend a quarter of my life on my phone, but how does it happen? For me, it was because of YouTube addiction. It was my bestie and, simultaneously, my Arch-enemy.</p>

<p>I made three rules, but they’re pretty simple. They should only watch YouTube videos if they are for learning, search 
videos only from the search box, not from the recommendations, and meditate for 10 seconds when I’m dying to watch YouTube. 
I installed ScreenZen on my iPhone to forbid watching YouTube on my smartphone. Additionally, I installed an extension called 
Unhook on my Mac browser to restrict the YouTube feature to only searching videos. I made this decision the day before 
last night and did pretty well yesterday. I did pretty simple things, but I started taking specific actions.</p>

<p>By this process, I specified the main problem, set a clear-cut rule, and created an environment that forced me to follow it. 
You can make your own rules following these steps. Then, we should admit that we’re addicted to our phones to escape from 
tasks that we don’t want to think about. I’m on my way to overcoming addiction, and I’ve tried it many times, but I can do 
that now. This is a question of our honors and determinations. If we can say goodbye to our phones and their addictions, 
we’ll get everything: a lot of time, concentration, life satisfaction, and so on. This is a fork in the road.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[It should be because of your phone if you feel you aren’t doing well. It consumes your time and is known as life. But you’ve already known this and don’t need to understand why you should do that anymore. I’ve recognized it for a long time, too. I deleted all social media apps on my phone, turned the gray color filter on, left only four apps on my home screen, and so on. But my screen time is still around 6 hours a day, and it gets 10 hours or more on a terrible day. It’s ridiculous that I spend a quarter of my life on my phone, but how does it happen? For me, it was because of YouTube addiction. It was my bestie and, simultaneously, my Arch-enemy.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Running Away from Pain</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/from-pain/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running Away from Pain" /><published>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2024-03-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/from-pain</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/from-pain/"><![CDATA[<p>I became a proactive truant and got depressed in my first year of high school because of the intimidating and closed environment and teachers. While at home, I was thinking about my purpose of attending school, studying, and living all the time. Eventually, I got a straightforward and obvious but essential purpose for living.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p>The reason why I am living is just to be happy. And if something bothers me, I can and should run away from it to be satisfied.</p>
</blockquote>

<p>After I got this value, my depression almost recovered, and I felt free. I transferred to a famous online high school in Japan in my second year. It was a great decision. I could make great friends and meet great teachers. More than anything else, because I had more free time, I was inspired by a classmate to participate in extracurricular activities such as organizing events and joining presentation competitions, which allowed me to learn about a new world that I had never known before. Also, it is a high school known as an advanced education system; there was an academic path support division of universities overseas, which kind of opportunity is rare in Japan. Because there was such support, I could join the online Oxford summer program and learn about the system of foreign universities to grasp and think about them deeply and rethink my life goals. As a result, I am now in a U.S. community college and aiming to transfer to 4 years university. I wish I had recognized myself sooner and escaped sooner before I became depressed.</p>

<h1 id="how-can-i-apply-this-lesson">How can I apply this lesson?</h1>
<p>So far, it’s been my story; I want to write what I can say from it from now on. We have to endure, but we also have to escape. Without context and background, we can’t decide which option to take. We need to consider whether there are enthusiastic dreams beyond the pain. We need to think critically and ask ourselves if we think so. Unsurprisingly, our lifetime is finite, and everyone will die. So, when we think about how to make the most of our limited 
time and be happy, it is highly contradictory and self-destructive to put up with painful situations that do not align with our dreams and goals. However, quitting what you have kept doing is risky, and you might need to find out whether the pain leads you to your enthusiastic dream. In that case, it will be very effective to take your time for holidays or vacations 
and do journaling or stuff like that to rest your mind. By taking distance from the pain temporarily, you observe your situation objectively. Running away from the pain is the opposite of running away from life. It entails happiness, dreams, and real life. The mindset we need to have is not a binary choice of whether to run away. It’s moving forward toward your objects to be happy. Regardless of what others say, your life is yours, and my life is mine.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="blog" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[I became a proactive truant and got depressed in my first year of high school because of the intimidating and closed environment and teachers. While at home, I was thinking about my purpose of attending school, studying, and living all the time. Eventually, I got a straightforward and obvious but essential purpose for living.]]></summary></entry></feed>